### MARKETING COORDINATOR AND GRAPHIC DESIGNER

## Professional Summary

Successful marketing leader with proven accomplishments in driving brand recognition and profits. Great leader with high energy, motivates self and others to maximize performance and take pride in their work. Diverse portfolio and numerous recommendations. ACCOMPLISHMENTS  $\hat{a}$   $\in$  Collaborated with team of five in research report that led to continued support for an international educational program  $\hat{a}$   $\in$  Redesigned YouTube channel to increase subscribers from 70 to 1,200, and average monthly views from 3,000 to 10,000.  $\hat{a}$   $\in$  Launched successful new product line that resulted in several account acquisitions. Skills

- Graphic design
- Print design
- Copy Writing
- Editing
- Video content and production
- Storytelling
- Project management
- Public Speaking
- Problem resolution
- Marketing analysis
- Team management
- Japanese Language
- MS Office
- Adobe InDesign
- SEO
- Balance, Exchange
- Basic, MS Office
- Catalogs, Newsletters
- Content, Online marketing
- Copy Writing, Print design
- Clients, Problem resolution

- Client, Project management
- Editing, Public relations
- Editor, Public Speaking
- English, Quality
- · Fiction, Research
- Fundraising, Sales
- Government, Seminars
- Graphic design, Strategic marketing
- Adobe InDesign, Teaching
- Japanese, Team management
- Layout, Video
- Team leader, Websites
- Magazine articles, Writer
- Marketing analysis
- Marketing
- Product marketing
- Market
- Marketing copy
- Meetings

### Work History

Marketing Coordinator and Graphic Designer , 10/2017 to Current Newsbreak – Bellevue , WA

- Devised and deployed online marketing plans with effective social media and video campaign strategies that increased monthly web visits by 40%.
- Improved product marketing by redesigning catalogs to increase product clarity and client outreach.
- Directed marketing projects at all stages, including conceptual planning, schedule management, and implementation.
- Developed insights on marketing campaigns to assess performance.
- Evaluated consumer preferences and behaviors combined with market trends to adjust and enhance campaigns.
- Headed preparation of marketing copy, images, videos, emails, and other collateral.

# Web Designer, Web Designer and Content Writer, 08/2016 to Current

- Interviewed clients to understand goals and products to place them in front of target customers.
- Designed site and layout for websites to balance sales pitch with education.
- Established basic SEO to improve placement and increase visibility.

## Coordinator, Instructor, 07/2009 to 01/2016

# NA

- Educated students on Internationalization and English as a foreign language applying variety of instructional techniques, including hands-on curriculum.
- Initiated new learning methods, promoting student comprehension and increasing interest in subject matter.
- Reviewed class records to look for areas in need of improvement and implement plans of action.
- Provided clear, informative lectures on culture, language, and discrimination to groups of 20-100+ students and parents.
- Worked one-on-one with special needs students to optimize comprehension and foster interest.
- Earned positive feedback from fellow teachers and parents.
- Organized and managed four+ skill development seminars for fellow educators in the region.
- Interpreted between Japanese and English at events with 10-150 participants and at government meetings.
- National Association for Japan Exchange and Teaching.
- Japan.

## Director of Public Relations, 06/2013 to 01/2014

Team leader and chief editor of research report presented to Japanese Ministry officials to ensure continued program support.

- Monitored marketing content for quality, accuracy, and impact.
- Led campaigns to increase constituent knowledge of association's work, increase transparency, and improve perception.
- Produced and distributed internal and external communications including newsletters, magazine articles, and event promotions.
- Coordinated with social media planner to create cohesive online presence, including Facebook and Twitter, and YouTube.
- Created and implemented goals, security standards, and disbursement plans for charity fundraisers.
- Determined target demographics and devised strategic marketing initiatives to reach target audiences.
- Oversaw and enhanced public relations and fundraising programs across all of Japan.

#### Education

B.A: Religious Studies, Asian Studies University of New Mexico

Graduated in Top 3% of Class, GPA: 4.0, Summa cum laude •Founding member of the Philological Society

Work History

Marketing Coordinator and Graphic Designer, 10/2017 to Current

Mitoyo City Board Of Education â€" City, STATE

- Devised and deployed online marketing plans with effective social media and video campaign strategies that increased monthly web visits by 40%
- Improved product marketing by redesigning catalogs to increase product clarity and client outreach.
- Directed marketing projects at all stages, including conceptual planning, schedule management, and implementation.
- Developed insights on marketing campaigns to assess performance.
- Evaluated consumer preferences and behaviors combined with market trends to adjust and enhance campaigns.
- Headed preparation of marketing copy, images, videos, emails, and other collateral.

# Web Designer, Web Designer and Content Writer, 08/2016 to Current

- Interviewed clients to understand goals and products to place them in front of target customers.
- Designed site and layout for websites to balance sales pitch with education.
- Established basic SEO to improve placement and increase visibility.

# Coordinator, Instructor, 07/2009 to 01/2016

### NA

- Educated students on Internationalization and English as a foreign language applying variety of instructional techniques, including hands-on curriculum
- Initiated new learning methods, promoting student comprehension and increasing interest in subject matter.
- Reviewed class records to look for areas in need of improvement and implement plans of action.
- Provided clear, informative lectures on culture, language, and discrimination to groups of 20-100+ students and parents.
- Worked one-on-one with special needs students to optimize comprehension and foster interest.
- Earned positive feedback from fellow teachers and parents.
- Organized and managed four+ skill development seminars for fellow educators in the region.
- Interpreted between Japanese and English at events with 10-150 participants and at government meetings.
- National Association for Japan Exchange and Teaching.
- Japan.

# Director of Public Relations, 06/2013 to 01/2014

- Team leader and chief editor of research report presented to Japanese Ministry officials to ensure continued program support.
- Monitored marketing content for quality, accuracy, and impact.
- Led campaigns to increase constituent knowledge of association's work, increase transparency, and improve perception.
- Produced and distributed internal and external communications including newsletters, magazine articles, and event promotions.
- Coordinated with social media planner to create cohesive online presence, including Facebook and Twitter, and YouTube.
- Created and implemented goals, security standards, and disbursement plans for charity fundraisers.
- Determined target demographics and devised strategic marketing initiatives to reach target audiences.
- Oversaw and enhanced public relations and fundraising programs across all of Japan.

# Skills

- Graphic design
- Print design
- Copy Writing
- Editing
- Video content and production
- Storytelling
- Project management
- Public Speaking
- Problem resolution
- · Marketing analysis
- Team management

- Japanese Language
- MS Office
- Adobe InDesign
- SEO
- Balance, basic, catalogs, content, Copy Writing, clients, client, Editing, editor, English, Fiction, fundraising, government, Graphic design, Adobe InDesign, Japanese, layout, Team leader, magazine articles, Marketing analysis, marketing, product marketing, market, marketing copy, meetings, Exchange, MS Office, newsletters, online marketing, Print design, Problem resolution, Project management, public relations, Public Speaking, quality, research, sales, seminars, strategic marketing, Teaching, Team management, Video, websites, Writer